

## **Casey Flynn**

# **Entrepreneur / Software Engineer**

#### I am Co-Founder & CTO @ Cobar Systems

#### My NPM Packages

I currently live in beautiful Boston, Massachusetts.

I'm the CTO & Co-Founder of Cobar Systems, a software, IT services company that provides web based solutions for businesses in the field of continuity management and disaster recovery. We develop intuitive and easy to use software that reduces ancillary business operations so that our clients can focus on their core activities.

Previously I have worked as a software engineer on the iOS development team for Intuit's TurboTax Snaptax in San Diego, CA, and as the lead software engineer at two Boston-based tech companies, Vox Supply Chain and Indivly. I specialize in the design, development and maintenance of highly scalable and extensible database-driven web applications.

I'm an aficionado of Node.js environment, Google's Angular.js Framework, the Require.js module loading system, JavaScript written via CoffeeScript and the Jade templating language. Feel free to send me a message if you'd like to chat with me about those, or any other technologies listed on this website.

## **Personal Information**

Date of birth August 4th, 1988 Address 332 Newbury Street Boston, MA USA

#### **Email**

casey\_flynn@cobarsystems.com

**Phone** 

774 573 4580

Website

www.cobarsystems.com www.clubbingowl.com solutions.clubbingowl.com

## **Employment**

2011 - now

## Co-Founder & CTO @ Cobar Systems

from October 2011 to now

#### **Boston, MA**

Cobar Systems is a B2B service company that provides web-based softwa solutions in the field of continuity management and disaster recovery. Johan Barlach and Casey Flynn founded Cobar Systems in October 2011 to innova the way organizations test their recovery strategies.

We sell a web-based management system for testing business continuing plans, ensuring preparedness of employees and answering the question of organizations "Will our recovery plans work during a real business disruption." Our system, called Themis, replaces email communication and excessoreadsheet that are currently used to manage business continuity testing, automatically distributes, collects and compiles testing data across a organization and tracks if requirements, set by compliance, are made Engagement of test participants is also improved through its mobile and table integration, which allows them to access and input exercise information anytime, anywhere. Unlike competitors, Themis is an application built solely of the purpose of improving preparedness in organizations through exercising.

Cobar Systems's solutions are built with modern web technologies; allowing for our product to load efficiently, remain responsive under high load conditions, be cross-platform and browser compatible, feature real-tin communication, and be highly extensible/maintainable by developers.

2013 - now

## Co-Founder & CTO @ ClubbingOwl

blog.dotcloud.com/clubbing-owl-drives-client-revenue

from January 2013 to now

#### **Boston, MA**

Chief software architect of the Clubbing Owl Venue Management at Marketing System.

Multi-platform & multi-lingual venue & promotion team management syste

that integrates with the Facebook API to give clients more trackable client da and viral exposure opportunities on Facebook.

#### 2011 - 2012

## Software Engineer @ MessageAMP

from 2011 to 2012

#### @MassChallenge Incubator in Boston, MA

Design, implement, and maintain scalable and extensible database driven we applications using advanced web development techniques such as low balancing, caching (numerous types), worker-servers, CDNs, etc

#### 2011 - 2011

## **Software Engineer @ RealAdventures**

from January 2011 to June 2011

#### **Boston, MA**

- Developed and test new features and views of RealAdventures.com usir PHP5, SQL, HTML4/5, CSS2/3, Javascript, AJAX, Google Maps API, PayPal APIs, and Facebook APIs
- Developed map-feature of RealAdventures.com to give advertisers abilit to create and display a map of their listing and relevant POIs using Google Maps API, Javascript, AJAX, MySQL/SQL, PHP, HTML, CSS
- Developed web-application to automate payments of RealAdventures.com affiliates using PayPal Adaptive Payments API, PayPal PHP SDK, MySQL/SQL, PHP, Javascript
- Perform database schema management on MySQL database of RealAdventures.com

#### 2010 - 2011

## Software Engineer Intern @ Intuit Inc



#### **Manager Evaluation**

"Comments: We highly recommend Casey as a SW Engineer to any employer"

from 2010 to 2011

#### San Diego, CA

- Developed/tested software ('SnapTax' and 'ItsDeductible') for iPhone/iO using Xcode and Objective-C
- Integrated 'SnapTax' with Facebook using Facebook's APIs & iOS SDK
- Performed programmatic image-analysis for OCR (Optical Character

Recognition) feature of 'SnapTax'

- Developed/tested software ('TimeCatcher') for Android OS using Eclipse and Java
- Developed product experience mockups for customer usability-testing using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and PHP

## **Education**

2008 - 2012

## **Northeastern University**

from 2008 to 2012

**Dual Major in Computer Science & Business** 

## **Skills**

### **Development**

Programming Languages

C, C++, Objective-C, Java, Ruby, PHP5, SQL, CSS3, Less, JavaScript (in both client and server environments), Regular Expressions, XML/HTML, ACL2/LISP, Dart, Jade,

CoffeeScript

Systems

iOS, Android, Linux (Ubuntu), Unix, Mac OS, Windows

**Applications** 

tmux, npm, bower, yeoman, Memcached, Redis, Gearman, Apache2, nginx, Varnish, Piwik, New Relic, Navicat, Cornerstone, svnX, GIMP/Photoshop, Apple Instruments, OpenOffice/MS Office, MySQL Workbench,

WireShark

**Frameworks** 

PHPUnit, ExtJS 4, ExpressJS (& express.io), Flatiron,

Codelgniter, Kohana, cakePHP, Rails (ROR),

SocketStream, qUnit

Libraries

jQuery, prototype, Doctrine ORM, AngularJS,

BackboneJS, RequireJS, Socket.IO, DNode, Mustache,

Hogan, EJS

**SDKs** 

Facebook JS, Facebook PHP, Paypal Adaptive Payments PHP, AWS ECS PHP, MailChimp PHP, Mandrill PHP, Stripe JS & PHP, Pusher JS & PHP, Google Maps JS (v2 & v3)

**APIs** 

Facebook Query Language (FQL), Facebook Graph, Facebook REST, Google Maps, Google Maps Geocoder,

Amazon ECS SES, MailChimp REST, Piwik REST

**DBMS** MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB, CouchDB

**IDEs** VIM (preferred), Aptana, Xcode, emacs, NetBeans,

Eclipse, PhpED, Visual Studio 2005, Dreamweaver,

Textmate, Sublime Text 2

VCSs Git, Perforce, Subversion

Data Formats JSON, XML (SOAP), YML

Protocols HTTP/HTTPS, SSL, Websockets, JSON-RPC

Build Tools ANT, Grunt

Unit Testing Frameworks

jUnit, qUnit, Mocha, busterJS

Other Continuous Integration, UML Diagram Design, ER

Diagram Design, Rackspace VPS, AWS (SQS, RDS, ElastiCache, EC2, S3, CloudFront), Heroku PaaS, CloudFoundry PaaS, CloudFlare, PHPFog PaaS, CloudControl PaaS, APC, BitNami, dotCloud PaaS, Pusher, crontab, HTML5 Pushstate/History API,

AGILE/SCRUM, GitFlow Methodology

© Casey Flynn - 2013